In this market, can a normal investor
like me just keep buying?
>> You know what? This seems too crazy. I
even got a little pessimistic at point.
>> Wow, that that's new.
>> [music]
>> Well, what happens if I go through a bad
decade? I've written about I have a book
on it and even I went against that
because of what was happening. Trust me
on this. The math on on this is
undeniable. Even if you perfectly timed
it, I was wrong and it happens, you
know? If I could only give you one line,
one investment piece of investment
advice, it would be this.
>> [music]
>> Interactive Brokers.
the lead
>> Depends on your time frame. That's
everything. Like if if you need the
money in the next 5 years, no. I would
say absolutely not. You should not be
buying right now. If you're this is a
retirement account for 20 30 years in
the future, I would say yes, cuz the
market will surprise you in many ways.
A year ago I was bearish. I'm now
bullish once again. Over the last year
because AI was seen so crazy, I got a
little bearish for the first time ever
and I reduced my stock exposure by, you
know, 20%. I went from a 100% stocks in
my retirement account to 80/20, which to
me that's like being bearish. And at
this point now I'm like, why am why did
I do that?
It's probably a bit of both, right? If
you look at the history of any large
technological change, there's always a
ton of players that rush and there's a
lot of capital that goes in. There's
always over investment and I guarantee
in this case there's going to be some
over investment, whether it's already
happened, whether it's going to happen
in the future, I don't know. Like we
can't predict the future. At the same
time it is a paradigm shift for a lot of
things. Anyone that's used, you know,
chat GPT, Claude, you know, Perplexity,
you name it. You've seen things like
wow, this can save me time and there's
now bots out there that can do things
and they're not perfect, but they can
save a lot of time. It's a question of
like the economics haven't I think fully
worn out yet, right? Cuz at the end of
the day AI could be just as good as a
human, but what if it's more expensive
than a human? Of Of everyone thinks the
cost of compute's going to keep coming
down to the point where it's cheaper
than than people. And if that's the
case, then that's great, but there's a
lot of things we have to think through
there. It's it's a it's a very complex
question. So, overall, I would say, yes,
there's over-investment, but also we we
know it's a paradigm shift. So, it's
both, and that's why it's so confusing.
If it was an obvious answer, we wouldn't
be having this debate right now.
>> Okay, that's really interesting cuz I
you turned a little bit bearish. So,
based on what? Like is that the earnings
or the sentiment tells?
>> Price over sales. It It just There were
too many things that just reminded me of
2021, and I think I got a little bit of
déjà vu. Like
Chamath was coming out with SPACs again.
Like I was seeing price to earnings. I I
overlaid the Nvidia price to sales with
the Microsoft price to sales in '99, and
like the they matched. Of course,
there's a lot of coincidences. I was
like, this is just too crazy. Like the,
you know, price to sales, I like that
metric more than earnings cuz earnings
can be manipulated with all sorts of
accounting tricks. Sales is like, that's
what you have. Like you have the price
of your company, and you have your
revenue. You can't To fake sales is like
straight-up fraud, and people very
rarely do that. People can play
accounting tricks with earnings. You
can't do that with sales. So, for me, I
was looking at these data series, and I
was like, this is like seems crazy than
the dot-com bubble, and I think it
There's just a lot of growth, and that
maybe justified it cuz a lot of that
growth has happened. I mean, look at
what happened with Anthropic. I think I
think I just read like they were 3
billion ARR, now they're 45 billion ARR
in a year. Like that is absurd growth.
That was So, the growth is coming, not
for every company, but for a lot of
them, and so maybe I was, you know, I
was too bearish because I just thought
the growth expectations were crazy, and
they they've happened. The growth has
come. And so, it's interesting whether
it'll keep coming. That's a that's a
second debate to have, but I think
that's why I got bearish cuz I just I
couldn't imagine a scenario where a
company would go from 3 billion ARR to
45 billion in a year, or anything even
close to that, and they've easily done
that. And so, that's just an example of
the type of stuff that's happening in
these markets.
>> Do you still remember the moment you
changed from being bearish to bullish,
and and why?
>> I I don't there's one moment. I think
it's a slow realization of these things
are happening and like a lot of like I
was looking at the data saying, "Hey,
this looks like this is the case. This
can't keep going." And then a lot of
they hit a lot of those targets, right?
They earnings keep going up and like a
lot of these things I didn't think were
were going to happen ended up happening
and so I was wrong and it happens, you
know? That's why for the most part I
just say like you have it it seems so
stupid to say this, but like you have to
ignore all of the stuff that's coming
out and just like what did what does
history say and history says just keep
buying. I've written about I have a book
on it and even I went against that
because of what was happening in the
moment, right? And so that's where I
think you you have to like override your
emotion. Now, I didn't do anything
crazy. I I no matter what even if this
market was even crazier than dot com, I
would still be buying US stocks. I would
just reduce how much I'm buying. And so
for me it's like I'm always buying US
stocks. It's just a question of how
much. Instead of going as I said in my
retirement account instead of going, I
you know, 100% into, you know, equities
which is like, you know, developed, you
know, world international plus US
equities. I said, "Okay, I'm going to
only do 80% into those." So I just
dropped my exposure a little bit and I
just kept buying from there. So I always
make micro shifts when I get quote
bearish, but I'm never bearish enough to
be like, "Oh, I'm selling out all my
stocks." I would never do something like
that cuz the data is overwhelmingly
positive. You should never do something
like that.
>> The mantra of the book is if I can only
give you one line, one investment piece
of investment advice, it would be this.
The continual purchase of a diverse set
of income producing assets. There's
three pillars to that. Continual
purchase, you're buying over time and I
show in the data like why this is true
even even if I gave you information
about the future, you would would better
off just buying every month and there's
chapters that cover that. The continual
purchase of a diverse set, so
diversification is at the heart of this,
and then of income-producing assets. So,
income-producing assets are anything
that can produce some sort of income.
That includes equities, that includes
fixed income, that includes real estate,
right? We can go down there. That does
not include things like gold, Bitcoin,
etc. Does that mean you shouldn't own
those? No, but I don't think they should
be the vast majority of your portfolio.
So, if you just take that mantra, the
continual purchase of a diverse set of
income-producing assets, I follow that
always. That is always my mantra. Now,
the question is, what am I buying,
right? So, I'm never stopping buying. No
matter what happens with US stocks, I
might shift from okay, I'm not buying as
much US stocks, I might buy more
international stocks, or I might
buy more fixed income, or I might buy
shift and buy some real estate. Like,
the the thing is I I never say in the
book you need to only buy US stocks, or
only buy international stocks, or
whatever. I don't follow that approach
whatsoever. I think you should be buying
a diverse basket, and yes, though you
might change the weights over time based
on feelings and things like that, and
it's hard to just stick with one
strategy for forever. I know everyone
says, "Oh, just just never look at it."
And if you can do that, great, but I
think you will if you're following
markets and stuff, you're going to get a
little emotional. So, you have to figure
out, how do I do this in a way that I'm
going to still be successful in the long
run, no matter what happens, right? So,
I might get a little emotional, and like
I said, shift from a 100 zero to an 80
20 portfolio, right? I might do a a
minor shift like that, and then I'll
keep buying going forward. So, I think
that's the framework you need to have as
an investor. It's like, what can I do so
no matter what happens, I'll be okay,
right? Cuz it's not going to be I think
a lot of people think it's like, oh, I'm
either going to have a 100 100% stocks,
or I'm going to have 100% cash. And I
think both of those are are in my mind
are failure. Like, you can't just do you
can't have both of those as a mindset.
You have to have something in between
where if the market rips upward, you're
great, and if the market crashes and we
go through the Great Depression, you're
fine, right? If you were 100% stocks in
1929, you would have been destroyed. If
you were 100% cash in 1980, you would
have been destroyed over the next 20
years because stocks did so well, right?
So, just every time period, I can tell
you when your portfolio would have
failed.
The only way to kind of get past that is
to have some form of diversification.
So, that's my approach there.
>> Just keep buying. Like, for example, S&P
500 index, right? Do you think that's
really conviction? I mean, that's
pattern recognition. You're just
trusting historical data, right? You're
trusting what has worked for the last
100 years. So, my question is, so how do
you build real conviction for the notion
of just keep buying itself?
>> I I understand your point completely.
You're like, where does the conviction
come from? And I think the conviction
doesn't just come from like, okay, we
have one country with a, you know, a
century of return. If you haven't read
the book Stocks for the Long Run, that's
an incredible book. Or Triumph of the
Optimists, there's a lot of great books
out there that kind of looks at that
look at different data series, not just
the US. And so, if you look at a
long-term approach across many developed
countries that had stock markets, and
you look at like how those markets
return over very long periods of time,
you have a very high conviction rate in
the sense of
markets are going to probably return
about 4% above Treasury bills, right? 4%
above the safe, whatever the safe asset
is, right, out there. 4% above cash,
let's say. And so, 4% may not sound like
a lot, but you do that and remember,
inflation-adjusted 4%, you do that over
the course of a century, it ends up
being a very, very good return. Now, of
course, the US has done about 7% above,
you know, inflation over the long haul.
So, I'm not I'm not expecting 7% going
forward. I think a lot of people do, I
do not. But, if you just stay 4%, I
think you can justify that across many
different equity markets across the
world, and you can do that with real
estate, with a lot of different
income-producing assets. Now, of course,
there's risk there, but if you have a
diversified portfolio, like you would
have done quite well over the last
century. And that includes having US
stocks, international stocks, having
real estate, etc. So, that's where this
conviction comes from. It comes from
diversification. Without
diversification, I agree with you. If I
just had to pick one stock or one
market, I would be a little worried,
right? If I just said, "Oh, I'm only
going to invest in, you know, Japanese
stocks or Korean stocks or Taiwanese
stocks." It would be a little worrying,
but if I could have something else in
the portfolio or
other types of assets that give me
broader exposure, then I would be far
less worried. So, I think that's where
the conviction comes from. Since at
least, you know, the 1800s, you know,
since the Industrial Revolution, we've
been producing humans as a whole have
been producing more and more and more
and more, and I don't think that trend
is going to stop. And so, that's where
the conviction comes from. It's that
long-term technological which we keep
managing to, you know, hit every single,
you know, every few years. We're still
on that curve. So, if you're going to
say that's pattern recognition, well,
what what isn't pattern recognition? At
some point, like everything is pattern
recognition. You're looking at a
business, you're looking at you're
looking at their balance sheet, and
you're recognizing some sort of pattern
of the revenue going up, right? So,
where where do we stop that argument, I
guess, is my question.
>> So, if you are buying into S&P 500, then
basically you are buying into the story,
the economy, the GDP, the future economy
is going up. Basically, you are buying
into that story. So, that's how I
personally get the conviction of buying
a broad-based index fund. You You are a
data guy, and your books are full of it.
You've been reading about investing for
for years now. Beyond the data, what
have you actually learned about investor
behavior and psychology that surprised
you over the last few years?
>> I think you just realize how difficult
it is to get over biases you have. Like,
I'm biased against real estate, and I
know this because of I lived through
'08. I lived in an area in Southern
California that had one of the worst
housing booms in the entire country. I
saw prices go from at the time, you
know, a house that was $250,000 got up
to about $600,000 within 2 years. That's
crazy to see that happen. You don't
expect your home to over double in price
within the within, you know, a 2-year
span. And so, I saw that happen. I then
I saw it blow up, and I saw people
underwater, like, you know, my own
family owed more money on a home that
they had than what it was worth, right?
So, it's called being underwater. The
mortgage is larger than the property
value after the crash happened. So, I
saw that, too. That's a bias I have. I
think in terms of behavioral things, you
have to realize what are your biases and
how do you overcome them or how do you
try to counteract them, right? So, I I
try to still own real estate despite the
fact that I'm kind of biased against it,
right? And even like I write about this
stuff. I have data. I do all this stuff
and I still, you know, have my moments
where I'm like, "Uh I'm this feels weird
to me." And I I make changes a slight
changes in my portfolio. So, it's like
what do you do to safeguard yourself
against your own behavioral biases? What
I do is I just I call it sinning a
little, which comes from Clifford
Asness. And he's like, "If you're going
to make a tactical change, aka go from
100 zero to 80 20, you make a slight
change. You don't bet the farm,
basically. You don't You don't move
everything at once, right?" And so, for
me, it's about making micro changes to
my portfolio that allow me to sleep at
night and kind of get past some of those
behavioral issues without really risking
anything for the long. So, that's the
big one there in terms of a lot of the
behavioral things I like to do. But, you
have to figure out like what are your
behavioral things? What are those things
for you that are causing you problems?
And then how do you find ways to trick
yourself so that you don't cause a big
long-term error from them?
>> I'll be honest with you. Uh my bias or
my preference is buying the dip. During
the COVID crash, I had been buying and
buying. Over the years, I I become the
the guys I don't buy when the when the
market goes crazy. I always buy the
dips. What was wrong with that?
>> The issue is let's just talk about a
market index. We can talk about
individual stocks after, but the general
issue is if you wait for a dip, a lot of
times when that dip finally comes, it's
going to be even higher. The price will
be higher than where you could have
bought previously, right? The story I
tell is I remember back in 2017, there
was an investor I knew and he was
telling me, "Oh, I only buy the dip. I'm
going to wait till there's a big crash
and I'm going to buy." And this is early
2017. So, he waited, waited, waited.
Finally, COVID happens. 2020, it's been
3 years, right? March 2020 in
particular, March 23rd, 2020, which was
the absolute bottom. At that point, the
market was 33% below its high, right?
Even if he perfectly timed it, which of
course he doesn't know he's at the
bottom. Is it going to keep going?
Should I wait? Where do I buy? So, put
all put all that aside. Even if he
perfectly knew the bottom and bought on
March 23rd, 2020, he still would have
bought at a higher price than if he had
bought back in 2017, like in early 2017.
So,
that's the my counterargument. It's like
a lot of times there's a dip. Oh, I got
a 5% dip, but you're buying at a 10%
higher price than you could have bought
before, right? So, I think that's the
thing people don't People don't go back
and say, "Okay, I'm not buying today on,
let's say, May, you know, 12th. I'm not
buying today, but I'm going to but I'm
going to wait till the next dip." And
then look and when you buy the dip, is
that price lower than the day you didn't
buy? And that's the question. And most
people don't do that. They don't write
it down. They never check and say, "Oh,
I bought it lower than what I could have
bought it at before, right?" And if you
wait too long, the market can just keep
ripping upward. And one last thing on
buying the dip, I think you have to
realize, and this is why I like using
history, the worst dip in, you know, US
market history was the Great Depression,
right? And do you know what happened?
You know, 1929, they talk about the
great crash and everything. That wasn't
even the worst year. The worst year was
from 1931 to 1932.
The market was already down, I think,
like 50% or something. So, like, you're
like, "Oh my god, this is a buying
opportunity." From 1931 to the summer of
1932, which was the bottom in, I think,
July, the market went down 60%. This is
after it already had 2 years of just
getting destroyed. So, you keep talking
about buying the dip, but at some point,
you may face a dip where it just keeps
dipping. Like, you could have said, "Oh,
the market's 50% down. I'm going to bet
everything I have on this." And then you
put all your money in, and then you lose
60% on that, and that is truly
destructive like nothing else. And so, I
know we haven't had one of those, and I
hope we never do, but if we ever come
into one of those scenarios, buying the
dip can get very scary and can destroy a
lot of capital very quickly. And so, you
just have to be prepared for that. I
know that's the worst-case scenario, but
I need to bring it out because that's
what can happen on the downside that
people don't really think about.
>> I I to talk about more about cash. Do
you think there's a case to be made like
for individual like me to have cash
besides your emergency fund?
>> I guess the question is like what what's
the need for that money? Is Are you If
you're waiting for it I'm guessing
you're doing it because you're waiting
for a dip and we've already talked about
why that may not be optimal. Now, I
understand why it's certain people like
that.
I personally don't do that. The reason
once again I'm holding cash is because
I'm trying to buy a house and so maybe I
am trying to like time the dip in the
real estate market if there's going to
be one. I don't know if there's going to
be one but either way I need to have
that cash if I end up buying at the
prices as they are. Like I still need to
have the cash to do it, right? Or I may
need to save up so much cash I put down
a larger down payment because of where
interest rates are, right? Because if
interest rates are 6% or 7%. I don't
want to borrow all that money at 7%. I'm
willing to borrow a much smaller amount
at 7% maybe but I don't want to borrow,
you know, 80% of the value of a property
at 7%. That's the, you know, most of it
if you know anything about how loan
payments work on a house. For me, the
cash thing is a personal thing. Why
would you have cash? It My question is
just why would you own cash
outside of like a need for a an actual
liability or thing you're going to buy
in your life? Outside of that, why would
you need, you know, cash? Outside of
emergency fund, outside of I need to buy
a house, I need to pay for a wedding,
something like that. Why would you need
it? Someone's like, "Well, I want to
wait for a dip or I want to buy a dip."
I see the argument but once again the
data doesn't support it. Most of the
time you're going to statistically most
of history you're going to buy at a
higher price. Your cash would have been
better deployed in that thing that you
wanted to buy already, right? Just buy
it now and just just take the plunge. Of
course, that's scary behaviorally. I
understand that.
>> What's interesting about Warren Buffett
is he himself is stock picker but he
advise against individual stocks to
normal investors and you also advise
against individual stock investing.
>> For most retail investors, I think if
you're going to pick individual stocks
and you want to do it because you enjoy
it, it's fun for you, great. Keep it at
like 5 to 10% of your portfolio and have
at it. Have fun. I'm not against it. I'm
just like, you got to reduce your
exposure cuz in the event that you're
wrong, it could go very badly. Or
obviously, if you're right, it'll do
well, but if it's only 5 to 10% of your
portfolio, it's like a nice to have,
right? I've come up with so many
different arguments looking at this. The
original argument that most people refer
to is what I call the performance
argument, which is just like if you look
at professional managers, people that do
this for a living, most of them, you
know, over a 5-year time period, it's
like something like 70 to 80% don't beat
their benchmarks. There's something
called the SPIVA reports, SPIBA.
You can look them up. You can look up at
different countries, all this stuff.
Most professionals don't beat the
benchmark, which is the S&P 500 or
whatever their target index market is,
right? If it's like Taiwanese stock
market, the Korean, etc. So, that was
the original argument. It was like,
"Hey, the performance argument. That's
why you shouldn't do it." Then I came up
with something called the existential
argument, which is like, "How do you
know if you're good at stock picking?"
You don't It's like, if if you and I
went to play basketball, anyone watching
could tell within 3 minutes who has
talent who doesn't, right? Me versus
LeBron James, if LeBron James wasn't
famous and we just went on the court,
you would know within a minute that he
was better than me, right? It wouldn't
take you any time. Now, let's say, Ray,
you and I went to pick stocks. How long
could it take before they knew whether
we were good? It could take years. It
could take a decade before you know who
actually has skill, right? And who's
just lucky. So, that's my next argument
is like, you don't know if you're just
lucky or not, right? And that's a
problem. And no one wants to look in the
mirror and be like, "Yeah, I just got
lucky with that." But that's the case a
lot of times. So, that's my second
argument against stock picking, which is
the existential point. And then finally,
I think my my best argument against is
actually just like, "Is that the best
use of your time?" Like, I I'm just
going to use myself as an example cuz I
don't know your audience is what or know
kind of what they do with their careers
are, but like if you gave me an hour,
right? What is the best use of my time
in that hour? For me, it's writing
something cuz I could go and I'm going
to generate more income from my writing,
from writing a blog post, helping to
write a book, whatever it is, than I am
from researching a stock, right? And
putting my money into that. So,
especially for those people that don't
have a lot of money, if you're just
starting out, like all that time you're
spending, you're going to make far more
money by just working a job or doing
something that's going to create income
is going to create you more than your
portfolio will. Now, on the flip side,
if you have a bunch of money already,
then yeah, I think stock research can
make you more money because you have a
lot of capital at your display, right?
You know, I I say you know, if you have
a thousand bucks and you get a 10%
return, that's a hundred dollars, which
is in the grand scheme of things is not
that much money, right? But if you have
a million dollar portfolio and you get a
10% return, that's a hundred thousand
dollars, which for a lot of Americans,
that's like a good decent job in the
United States, right? So, you can see
you could get that return in a year. So,
the stock research and beating the
market and all that only makes sense
once you have a ton of money. If you
don't really have a lot of money, it
makes no sense to waste your time on
that, right? So, obviously, you can't
get good unless you spend time
researching it, so I get that, but at
the same time, like I think most people
would be better spent in terms of their
financial success if they spent that
time on their career than on just trying
to pick stocks.
>> Yeah, I remember in your book you said
something like this, "Savings is for the
poor and investments is for the
wealthy." The other day I I sent a tweet
on X, I said, "People really should
focus on their income, especially if you
are young, right?" And I got this reply,
he said, "If it were that easy to
increase my income, I wouldn't be
investing in the stock market." So, what
does this reply tell you about the
mentality of the the new investors?
>> Well, it's it's not easy. No one said,
"Oh, yeah, just increase your income is
the easiest thing." It's not you can't
just hit a button that's going to
increase your income, but like think
about your long-term career and like
what you can do to increase your income.
And I I'll give, once again, I I can
only give my example cuz I don't know
every single person, right? But like in
my example, I said, "Hey, I want to
start writing. I want to write about
something I love. I want to build that
craft." For three years, I didn't make
any money doing this. No nothing, zilch,
right? And then finally I started
running ads on my blog. Then I had book
deals, then I'm starting to do speaking
stuff, right? So, it's one of those
things that like I'm not saying that's
going to happen for every person, but if
you take a long-term approach to your
career and you put in enough work, like
you will see some results. I'm not
saying you're going to be a household
name, I'm not saying you're going to be
a famous celebrity. I'm just saying
you're going to see something that's
going to be, you know, a decent result
for all the work you put in. And you
have to work at it and it takes a long
time, but like I've seen the succeed.
I've seen a lot of people succeed in
this way. It just takes more time than
you think, but you have to be diligent
about your career. And so, you're right,
like if if the choices are like, "Okay,
I don't want to put in any effort or I'm
going to just do the stock market."
Like, yeah, putting in no effort is
going to not is not going to beat the
stock market, but you need to put in
some effort to try and boost your career
to have more income, so then you can
actually play the stock market actually
make more money, right? Like in a given
day now, if the market's up or down a
lot, I'll make more or lose more than I
made, you know, in like a really good,
you know, half a year when I first
started, right? So, it's one of those
things where as your portfolio gets
bigger, the swings on it get so large
that it's just like you could end up
making so much more money than you ever
could have when you first started
working. So,
focus on your career, but then use that
to build your investments.
>> Yeah, I used to share you my channel. I
said, um, you cannot get rich in the
stock markets before you get rich
outside the markets. And a lot of people
are arguing like like pushing back like,
"No, there it seems to be a lot of
people are getting rich inside the
market." So, you're a data guy. Do you
have any data on on this to share some
insights? Like so, is it true like there
are more and more people are getting
rich solely by investing in stocks?
>> The data overwhelmingly supports a model
where people are saving over time and
putting it into the market, right? It's
their careers. Like if you actually look
at like what's the most correlated thing
with wealth, it's income. It's not
There's no debate. You can look at every
data set. I've actually looked I did a
course for um I did just keep buying a
course in Taiwan and I looked at like
some Taiwanese like financial data and
if you look at savings rates and
incomes, they're positively correlated,
which means people with higher incomes
save more money. Now, what do I mean
save money? They save it and they
probably invest it or they buy a
property, right? So, if savings rates
are correlated with income, that means
that those people that have higher
incomes are going to have more money to
invest, right? Every single data set
I've seen shows that. Does that mean
there's not someone who bought a stock
that ended up going up 100x and made
money? Of course not. People get lucky.
Those types of things happen and maybe
they weren't lucky, maybe they have
really deep skill at identifying these
stocks, that's great. But, in general,
those types of things are quite rare,
you know, you don't see those too often.
So, with the the most common way people
get rich is by either working a job and
saving for a long time or starting a
business and selling that for a lot of
money, right? Or having some sort of
equity in a business. Maybe they're on a
startup and they get equity and then
they the business just gets really,
really big and they sell that. So, one
way or another, it's either some sort of
equity ownership in a in a private
business or it's working at, you know, a
high-income career for a long time,
right? So, that's what the data shows
and I've analyzed that so many different
ways. So, it's not that you can't get
wealthy in the stock market. I guess the
question is how wealthy is one and then
two, over what time scale are we
talking?
>> I want to ask you one final question
about the market and the current
situation. So, what's your opinion on
selling and taking profits? Like the
market is so high, should people take
profits?
>> I guess my question is what are you
selling for? Once again, this is always
going to be an individualized answer.
Like, okay, if right now I were to sell,
let's say I was forced to sell all my
stocks, like what would I do with that
money? Like I Am I going to go buy a
bunch of stuff? Like no, if I wanted
something, I'll just go buy it now,
right? I don't need to
sell something to go buy for no reason,
right? So, it's like what are you going
to use that money for? If you're like,
"Oh, I need to sell and take profits
because I need to go and buy a house or
I need to go and fund this thing or pay
for a wedding or whatever it is." Then,
yes, taking profits makes sense. If
there you have a legit real-life reason
to use the money, do it. But, taking
profits just to take profits, like I
don't always see the point in that. Now,
if you're like, "Well, I'm doing this to
diversify." That's a different argument,
right? I think taking profits and
diversifying can be aligned, but they
don't have to be. So, before we say,
"Hey, let's take profit." That's a
taxable event in a lot of cases, so you
have to pay taxes on all that. The
question is like, "Why are you taking
profit?" Are you taking profit to
diversify? Great. Are you taking profit
just because? Like, are you going to use
it to buy something? Okay, but like if
you don't know why you're doing it, you
shouldn't do it is my is my point.
>> Now, let's move on to what to buy and
how to buy it. And do you mind sharing
with us like what what are you buying?
What kind of adjustment you did over the
years?
>> I can just give you like kind of a
long-term history of my allocation. So,
when I started in 2012,
I was like 85% equities, 15% US bonds.
And so, the equities were split I've
always basically been split 50/50
between US stocks and then
international. And then even the
international split in half between
developed and emerging. So, it's really
like and that 85% share has shifted over
time, right? So, that 85% at one point I
was 100 zero. I got tired of bonds after
like two to three years, so I was 100
zero. And I said, "Wait, why am I doing
this?" So, I added bonds back, right?
So, I would say right now my portfolio
of my investable assets is like probably
in yeah, 85 20 or we'll say 80/20, not
85/15. So, it's probably still 80/20. It
actually hasn't changed much. Like,
there's other pieces that have come and
gone. I sold gold a long time ago. I
bought gold back. Those types of things
have happened, but once again, that's
been less than 5% of my portfolio when
you include gold and Bitcoin and Arc and
things like that. Those represent like
less than 5% of my portfolio. The only
other big change, which has nothing to
do with investing, is more my personal
life, is like I've been buying way more
Treasury bills, so my cash pile is going
up because I'm trying to buy a house. I
have a legit reason. I need to pay a
down payment. So,
once again, if we include those assets
in my portfolio, my allocation would be
more like,
you know, 35% bonds and 65% stocks, but
I don't I don't know if we should
include that because I have a specific
need for that, right? So, I think a lot
of times when we talk about investing,
you know, we always say, "Look, let's
just look at all your money, and that's
your portfolio." But, like, if some of
that money is set aside for a need, or I
want to buy a house, I don't know if you
would include that in my like risk asset
portfolio, right? Or like, what my
portfolio is going to do in the future.
So, I think there's different ways to
think about this. So, if you include my
Treasury bills, yeah, I'm probably like
35% fixed income, which for someone my
age, it doesn't I don't you know, I'm
only 36 years old. I wouldn't
necessarily want to be 35% fixed income,
but at the same time,
until I buy a house, and once I buy one,
then yes, I'll go back to probably
80/20, you know. All the rest of those
assets will move back once I have Once
that money's reallocated into a house.
So, I think that's another piece of this
is like it's really dependent on your
life situation, what's going on. Like,
you know, my wife and I got married last
year. We just had our first child, uh
you know, a few months ago. So, it's
like one of those things where like
because of changes in my life, my
portfolio is changing to reflect that.
And this has nothing to do with what I
think about the future of markets, or I
have more cash than ever because I think
AI is going to like No, it's nothing to
do with that. It's just my personal
situation. I think more investors would
do better if they just thought more
about like just what's your actual
situation, what do you really need the
money for? Most people don't I think ask
that question, and they just invest
based on like, yeah, there's data and
all that, but like, what are you
actually going to do with the money? If
you don't know, there's kind of no
point, really. Like, the whole point of
investing is like I give up consumption
now to have more consumption in the
future, right? That's the idea, right?
So, the question is like, what are you
giving that up for? What are you using
it for? If you never end up using it,
what's the point? This is all just for
show. It's like Monopoly money in that
sense.
>> A lot of my viewers are actually passive
investors. So, when they hear the notion
just keep buying, to to them is S&P 500.
Let's Let's talk about S&P 500. So, it
it it seems like all those AI companies
are going to dominate S&P 500. So, if I
as a normal investor buy into S&P 500,
does does that put me in into a you
know, a relatively concentrated
position? Is not diversified enough?
>> It depends. I mean, in some ways yes,
it's more tech heavy. And so, the
question is do you want to buy an equal
weight S&P 5 instead of S&P 500 market
weight, you buy an equal weight. You
could do something like that. I think
that's fine. If you want to offset that
by owning stocks from another country
that where that country is not as tech
heavy, that's fine too. But like tech's
a large part of the economy because it's
came come to dominate a lot of stuff. If
you went back to the you know, the late
1800s, and you would have had a
railroad. Like, what was the Dow or the
you know, you would have had railroads.
That was it. That was the economy. It
was railroads, right? So, it's like this
type of stuff happens. Today, the S&P
500 is still like the most diversified
market even with all that concentration
in there. It still has a lot of other
things, financials, right? Uh there's
all sorts of other sectors in there, you
know, energy that that matter and that
can impact your portfolio. Like, I would
say in general most non-US equity
markets are more concentrated than the
US is because, you know, a lot of times
it's like, "Oh, well, we have this one
big company." And that big company
happens to be in this. It's like in a
smaller country. And so, it's like
that's all that's our stock market. Your
stock market is usually one or two of
those companies that just dominate the
entire index. So, with the with the US
market, at least you have other options
even though yes, it is getting
concentrated. But there's still quite a
few um
non-tech companies in the S&P.
>> Another concern about S&P 500 is Um, a
lot of my viewers they they hold this
mantra like they don't go with the herd.
It seems like everybody's now is buying
S&P 500. So, first I want to ask you, is
that true? And secondly, does that
create a problem like a self-feeding
loop? Like I mean, a lot of people are
arguing passive investing itself is
creating a bubble
and create some risk to the investment
market. I want to hear what you think
about this.
>> I mean, this this topic has been debated
for It's been debated since like started
in the '70s really, but passive didn't
really start taking off more until the
'90s and even more recently. So, yes, is
everyone buying the S&P 500? In a lot of
ways, at least in the United States,
yes. People are buying their 401(k)s,
they have it in their IRAs, they buy it
on their brokerage accounts. Like, uh so
many people have exposure to this. Is
that creating a self-perpetuating loop?
Yes, in a lot of ways, but like if every
2 weeks or I think about this, we have
401(k), which is just like a retirement
plan where every 2 weeks when you get
paid, some of that money comes out and
goes into a an investment account. Well,
if that investment account has the S&P
500, that means we're always buying the
S&P 500. And so, there's millions and
millions of workers in the United States
that are doing this every 2 weeks. So,
as long as people keep making money and
keep buying that, there's going to be a
bid there. There's going to be people
buying those shares. Now, what's going
to undo that? If the economy crashes,
people lose their jobs, they stop buying
these things, they stop having that.
Could that happen? Of course, but once
again, that is a very dark scenario. The
economy's changed a lot and you're like,
is that going to undo a lot of the
buying power? Yes, would that cause
prices to fall? Yes, but once again,
there has to be this huge thing that
happens in the economy that causes that.
As long as people are still making
money, there's still jobs, people are
still contributing to their 401(k),
there's going to be a bid there. Now,
whether that distorts prices of other
companies, I think is debatable. Like,
how how would Nvidia have gone from
where it was to where it is from passive
investing? It didn't. That was active
flows that did that, right? People saw
that sales went up, earnings went up,
and then they bid up the price, right?
That's not passive doing that. Passive
didn't say I didn't say, "Hey, in my
401k, put more in Nvidia." No one can do
that, right? In most 401ks, you cannot
do that. So, as a result, like I think
active markets are still working. I
think price discovery is working quite
well. So, I don't think that's
distorting those things. Maybe it's
distorting the market as a whole, but I
don't think it's messing with relative
prices all that much, in my opinion.
>> You You know, your book used that um we
should just keep buying those
income-producing assets. And
interestingly, you mentioned the gold,
art, crypto. You You have some of those
in your portfolios. Probably you do.
What's the reason behind that?
>> I think these were just hedge assets as
like a way of like, "Hey, I don't know
if this is going to be a thing, but I
own them as like a hedge." And like, you
can look at some of the historical data.
I've run like you can run these
portfolio optimizers, which is like,
"Hey, given all these asset classes,
what was the optimal portfolio?" Which
means like the highest return for level
of risk you take. And for example, I ran
this back I think in like
2019 or something, and it was like you
need to have 2% Bitcoin. So, I've had 2%
Bitcoin in my portfolio ever since. It's
the highest return I can get with the
least amount of risk I can take, right?
And so, I've had 2% Bitcoin. Obviously,
it's gone up and down. I sold at one
point some of it to get back to 2% cuz
it went up too much. And now it's come
down. I almost had to buy more because
recently like the price came down. It
didn't get to the point where I needed
to get back to 2%, but it got close. And
so, you know, I I just kind of let it
sit there. It doesn't really do much. I
haven't done any Bitcoin stuff in a long
time. Gold has come and gone. Um
I think with everything that's happened
over the last year, we we've seen that
the dollar dominance is now being
questioned in some ways. And so, I think
that's why the gold run happened. Um
what what's going to happen in the
future, I don't know. So, that those are
non-income-producing. And so, once
again, those are less than Overall,
those are like less than 10%. I'd say
about 5% of my portfolio. And art is
like basically nothing. I had like it
was like 1% of my portfolio at one
point. Um but when you put all that
together, like you look at all this
stuff and it's like that's not a
convincing. All this stuff I really
focus on once again is mostly equities.
That's going to be US, international. I
have like REITs, which is like a real
estate exposure cuz I don't actually
have any physical real estate yet. Um
you can do farmland if you want. I have
not. I I want to at some point. I just
haven't gotten around to it yet. I think
because of that I'm saving to buy a
house. I think once I have a house then
I can I don't want to go and start
investing in farmland and I don't have a
house yet. I think that's kind of weird
to me. So, you can do royalty investing.
There's so many options out there. I
talk about a lot of these things and
obviously I have fixed income, but the
main one I think if you look at just the
record of history, it's going to be
equities. It's going to be businesses
and that's where most of my money is
going to be for the rest of my life.
>> In this market, is is there still a case
for individual investors to consider
bonds?
>> Uh yes, there are definitely there's a
case for that in terms of I personally
recommend short-term. So, anything with
a duration of less than 5 years. I don't
like having anything long-term because
what what we saw I think the best
example of this was, you know, the rate
increase from 2021 into 2022. Anyone
that bought long-dated bonds got
destroyed because as as you know when
rates go up, prices go down and vice
versa. So, guess what? If you were
holding a lot of long-dated bonds in
2021 when rates started to shoot up into
22, you got destroyed. So, the 60/40 had
its worst year ever I think in 2022. Um
it's one of those things where you got
to just keep your duration short. And
the thing that people don't know about
ETFs, if you're buying a let's say a
it's let's say the duration's 10 years,
right? When you own the ETF, it's
resetting that duration every day or
every so often when the bonds mature,
you're always in a 10-year duration.
It's not like oh, I buy today and then
10 years from now and then my duration
zero and I get all my money back. It's
not like an an individual bond. You're
always resetting your duration. So,
you're always taking interest rate risk
over a 10-year period, which
people I'm not saying you can't do that,
but a lot of people don't realize that's
what they're doing. And so, you don't
want to be taking that risk when rates
are at all-time lows because all it
takes is a crazy event like that where
rates shoot up a ton and then you just
get destroyed. So,
um I'm not against bonds. I'm definitely
for them, but I'm short duration if I'm
ever going to do that. There's a lot a
lot of history on this, at least in the
US,
the highest, you know, return per unit
risk bonds were the five-year
Treasuries, right? So, anything five
year or less was the way to go. Once you
went beyond five years, the risk return
just wasn't there.
>> So, recently I realized that a lot of my
friends they they started to uh start
buying options, and they say like I we
are a long-term we are long-term
investors. We are, you know, selling
calls and got that that cash and
reinvesting into our stocks. So, so
what's your opinion on using margin,
using debt to fund your investment?
>> The question's always the rate, right?
If someone said, "Hey Nick, you could
borrow all this money for no cost," I
would do it in a second, right? But if
they it's always about the rate. And And
if I said, "Hey, I'm going to let you
borrow, but the the daily interest rate
is 100%." I'm coming up with something
crazy where the the annualized rate's,
you know, in the tens of thousands,
right? You would say no, right? At At At
the extremes, you can see why it doesn't
make sense, right? At a 100% daily
interest rate, makes no sense to have
debt. At 0%, it makes sense. Where that
personal number is for you,
that it's going to differ by person. In
general, I say don't do it because the
only guarantee from all this is that
you're going to owe interest on the
debt. That's the only thing I can
guarantee. You don't know what your
investments are going to do. Those
people selling call options, yeah, it
looks great now, that money's coming in,
but they say it's like picking up
nickels in front of a steamroller. One
day, you're going to miss the nickel and
you're going to get run over. And so,
it's, you know, Taleb has this thing
called the turkey problem where there's
a turkey and a farmer has this turkey,
and every day he feeds the turkey, and
the turkey gets fatter, and then and the
the turkey starts saying, "Wow, these
humans love me. Wow, the humans are so
great. Every day they bring me more food
and I get bigger and my feathers get
nicer every day. And then all of a
sudden on the very last day that the the
farmer comes with the
you know, a cleaver and cuts his head
off, right? And so you see the the
confidence of the bird goes up and then
it just falls like that. That's what
selling call options is like. You get
more confidence. Oh my god, I'm right.
I'm a genius. Look at all this money.
Look at all this money. And then one day
you have this a market event you
couldn't have foreseen and then you lose
everything, you know, or you lose most
of your profits right there. So, I'm not
saying that happens to every person, but
these types of things have happened. You
can look up uh there's a fund XIV, SIV.
Um look up that fund. Look what happened
to that fund. That's an example of
people picking up pennies. It's just
like selling call options, very similar.
You People are like, "Oh my gosh, low
volatility this thing's great." Until
volatility you ripped up where this
thing got destroyed and it went
bankrupt. So,
just keep that in mind like it's one of
those things like understand the turkey
problem and understand
how am I investing and is it like the
turkey problem or is it like something
else? And so, that's where I would
caution using debt.
>> Let's talk about how we should get by.
You you mentioned in the book we're
better off to DCA, but well in terms of
dollar cost averaging, I I found there's
a misunderstanding there. What exactly
is dollar cost averaging?
>> The problem is there's actually two
different definitions, which is why it's
so confusing. So, the original
definition, which comes from Benjamin
Graham, which is Warren Buffett's
mentor, is
buying over time. You're just buying
Every time you get paid, you have money,
you buy, right? You're buying an
individual stock, you're buying an index
fund. It doesn't matter what you're
buying. You're just buying over time.
That is different from the other
definition of dollar cost averaging,
which is you have a bunch of money
today. Let's say you have a hundred
thousand dollars and you say, "Hey, I'm
going to buy ten thousand dollars a
month. I'm going to wait kind of what I
call averaging in." You average in. You
kind of slowly wade into the market,
right? That's also called dollar cost
averaging. As you can see, this is quite
confusing cuz they're kind of different,
right? One and the other are They're
very different from each other. They're
literally the opposites from each other,
which is couldn't be more like One of
them is saying, "Hey, as soon as you get
the money, invest." The other one is
saying, "Hey, when you have the money,
slowly buy in." And I'm I'm against the
slowly buying one. I'm and fully support
of the one where you buy right away,
right? So, you could say someone buying
in their retirement account every 2
weeks in their 401k is dollar cost
averaging. You could also say that
someone who sold a business and now is
sitting on a lot of money in their
slowly waiting in is also dollar cost
averaging. That's where the confusion
comes in.
Generally,
buy quickly, sell slowly. That's my
mantra. Makes it much easier. So, if
you're like, "What should I do in this
scenario?" Buy quickly, sell slowly.
That genuinely makes you the most money
historically in basically every asset
class.
>> I'm not the guy DCA. I'm more of the
guy, you know, like averaging in. But I
think there's a reason behind it because
I'm I do not have a paycheck. I do not
have a salary. So, I run my own
business. Usually, the money doesn't
come like a steady stream. So, that
creates a problem. What do you say to
people like me who are either
freelancers, creators, or run run their
own small business? So, usually, their
money comes in a chunk, and that makes
it really, really difficult for them to,
you know, to DCA because you don't know
what happens to your business tomorrow,
right?
>> Yeah, that's a very different scenario
because you don't have that consistent
flow of money or where you know, "Hey,
I'm going to get paid in 2 weeks." My
only slight counter to this or someone
wants to average in, or you want to call
it, over time, I think that's fine. The
question is, how long you taking to
average in? That's the most important
variable, right? On average, and this is
just what the data shows, if you take 1
year, let's say you have $120,000,
and instead of you have two choices.
Let's just say there's only two choices.
You put in $120,000 today, or you put in
$10,000 a month for the next 12 months.
So, by the end of 12 months, you're
fully invested. So, those are two
options, right? Option A, buy now.
Option B, you kind of average in.
On average, historically in US stocks,
the second option, you would have
underperformed by on average by about
4%. So, if you're willing to give up 4%
so you don't experience a huge crash
right after, that's fine. And I think a
lot of people are willing to do that.
They're saying, "Hey, behaviorally,
it's okay if I lose 4% of that as long
as I don't experience an outcome where
the market crashes right away." Okay,
that's fine. And so, and you're like,
"Well, Nick, I what if I only take 6
months to average in?" Okay, then the
average loss is 2%, right? You take you
roughly a half of it, right? So, no
matter how you look at it, you just have
to accept, okay, on on average, here's
what's probably going to happen, so I
can just accept that up front and then
make your decision. That's how I would
view it. So, if you're okay, if you're
comfortable saying, "Hey, I'm willing to
take a little bit of a haircut to take 6
months to to average in with this
money," that's fine. Just don't take 5
years to do it cuz that's where the the
performance differences start getting
quite large.
>> You already you mentioned that you did
some adjustment to your uh buyings. So,
what's the reason behind I should adjust
the frequency or the amount of a money I
should uh DCA into the market?
>> It's up to you, really. Once again,
you have to do whatever's going to work
for you behaviorally. I can sit here and
talk till I'm blue in the face telling
you, "Hey, here's what the data says,"
whatever. If you don't feel comfortable
with it, don't do it. Like, I
I once again, at the end of the ti- at
the end of the day, is it worth 4% to
have, you know, not be able to sleep at
night? No, just average in. Okay, you're
you're probably going to lose 4% on
average. That's it. It's 4%. It's not
the end of the world, right? You'll
live. It's not one of those things where
like it's going to make or break your
financial plan. I think a lot of things
we get so obsessed I this is called
majoring in the minor, where we get so
obsessed. And this is not just true in
finance, this is true with so many
things. We get obsessed with the most
minor details that are going to have no
real impact on your life. Like, let your
life Remember, your life's up here. Your
financial life's one piece of that.
Like, we're talking about the smallest
detail in one part of your financial
life, let alone the rest of your life,
your health, your friends, your family.
Like, there's so many parts of your
life, and we're sitting here and arguing
over the most minor detail in one small
portion of your life. And I think we
miss the big picture. How is that going
to affect the entire financial pie, and
then how is that going to affect your
whole life? Whether you decide to buy
now or wait 12 months, it's kind of
irrelevant, honestly. I'm not trying to
dodge the question, cuz I've done Like,
I've done all that, so I spent years
doing that, and now I'm like zooming
out. I'm like, well, I mean, it was cool
I did it, but I don't I don't see the
purpose in these things anymore, because
it's like it's not going to affect your
financial plan. It's not going to have
any impact on whether your family loves
you, whether you're a good person. Like,
it doesn't do anything, right? So, it's
like it's fun to know, but just just
pick something and move on. Focus your
energy on other things, your health, or
something else, you know?
>> People who read your book and followed
it have been doing a pretty well during
the past several years. But, when they
go on social media, they see other
people posting massive gains. I I see on
my Twitter feeds, like, okay, this is so
easy. This is up $1 million this year.
I I quit my job because of Nvidia or
those semiconductor stocks, right? I
10x'd. So, even though your own
portfolio is winning, like, you feel
like you're losing because everyone is,
you know, seems to be winning more and
faster, right? So,
so what do you actually say to that
person? So, how do you stay sane in a
bull market where social media makes it
feel like everyone is making more than
you? Do you feel that pressure?
>> no, not at all. I mean, to be honest,
not that one. I mean, I feel different
types of pressure, different things, but
not that one at all, because it's the
it's it's the turkey problem disguised
as something else. Now, it's not as it's
not as bad as the turkey problem, but
it's kind of like it, because it's like
you have someone who's taking a strategy
now I'd be quite risky, and they're good
They might be doing well now, and if
they quit, if they they "Hey, I'm done.
I quit my job. I'm not going to keep
risking my money." They're going to
probably do fine. But what happens, and
you'll see, these people cannot quit.
Like, I've seen it with crypto. People
I've read stories of crypto people who
were up, you know, eight figures. They
had $10 million. That is a ton of money.
Did they Did they sell everything, go
into Treasury bills, and just live their
life off of, you know, what is what's 4%
of that? 400,000? They could live off of
$400,000 a year, 4% rule, for the rest
of their life, never have to worry about
it, right? Did they do that? Most did
not. They kept playing the game, and
then, oh, I'm down 90%. I've seen people
round trip up to seven, you know, seven
figures into the millions, and then back
down, you know. I have a good friend who
bought these Solana monkey um NFTs. He
had seven of them. He spent, I think,
$350, 250 bucks, something like that.
Like, literally, almost nothing. At one
point, he had over a million dollars.
All in after he paid taxes and
everything, and then everything crashed,
and he sold, he got 90,000. So, he still
took 300 bucks and turned it into
90,000. Insane, right? It's It's That's
a lot of money, right? It's not nothing.
But he could have had a million if he
sold the top, but it It's hard to know
that, right? He didn't know where the
top was. He kept going, and then he lost
a ton He lost more than he made, right?
But he still made a ton. So, it's It's a
weird example. These things happen.
They're quite rare. Number one, social
media is quite rare. You're only going
to see the winners, you know. It's very
rare that people are like, "Oh my god,
look at how much money Who's going to be
like, "Hey guys, look at how much money
I lost." Very rare. It does happen, but
it's rare, right? So, that's one thing.
You're not going to see all the losers.
And that kind of biases you. And then
two, like, how does it impact like your
long-term Once again, what's your
long-term financial plan? How's it
impacting you like going and trying
these strategies? The only version of
success I care about is whether you
survive. That's it. You can be like,
"Look, I have way more money than you,
Nick." Great, that's fine. If you're If
you made that money following a risky
strategy, I will say good luck to you,
because if you don't quit that strategy,
it's very likely in the end you'll end
up losing a lot of that money and then I
might end up having more than you and
it's not even about that but you get my
point, right? The only thing that
matters is do you just survive to the
end? Can you use your money to live the
life you want? That's the ultimate only
thing that matters and so can you use
your money to live the life you want? If
so, great. If not, then maybe you need
to change your strategy. So, I'm living
the life I want to live. I think that's
what's important to me.
Are you doing that for yourself? That's
the question I have to to the viewer.
So, stop worrying about other people
because you don't know what's going to
happen to them. You don't know the end.
You just know the middle or like the
beginning chapter, the middle. You don't
know the ending of that story yet and so
it's very easy to say, "Oh, I'm doing
the wrong thing." You don't know how
that's going to turn out and even if it
does turn out a certain way, they could
just get lucky. You don't really know.
That's the That's the problem with a lot
of these things. You don't know the
difference between luck and skill in a
lot of these areas.
>> A lot of people say, "With market this
high, the investors that are in the most
awkward position are the new ones who
just started. They have this fear that
I'm buying to a really, really high
market and the chances is going to be
against me in the future."
>> You're not going to like my answer but
I'm going to say it really doesn't
matter that much for the new young
investor and when I say that I'm
assuming the new young investor does not
have a lot of money to lose to begin
with. Let's be honest. So,
it doesn't matter that much. So, what do
I say to focus on? Focus on your career.
You're going to make so much more money
if you focus on your career over the
long term. What skills can you build?
How can you learn to use AI better? How
can Whatever. There's a lot of different
careers out there and there's a lot of
different things you can do. Do you want
to make content? Do you want to create
software? Whatever it is, figure that
thing out. That's way more important
than what's happening with the market.
And you're right, like, "Well, what
happens if I go through a bad decade?"
It's better to go through a bad decade
at the beginning of your investment
career than the end. Trust me. You do
not want the bad decade in the last
year. You want your best decade to be
the last decade you ever invest when you
have the most money to lose. Trust me on
this. The math in on this is undeniable.
You can do like if you're putting a
Let's say you put a thousand dollars a
year and the market's going up five
years then down five years or you have
the market go down for five years then
up for five years by the same magnitude,
it's far better to go down then up. You
will end up with more money, right? And
because you guess what? By year five you
have more money invested. You have more
money added to the pile. So when you
come back up over the next five years,
you end up making so much more money. So
trust me, you want the the bad you want
the bad stuff now. So I'd rather be a
young investor today than all else equal
with my assuming my career was the same,
I'd rather be a young investor today
than starting in 2012. I'll tell you
that much.
>> One is the to focus on their income.
Another thing is focusing on learning
about investment. If I'm a young
starting investor, I don't have a lot of
income. I'm focusing on my income but at
the same time I wanted learn about
investing. So where should I start?
>> I mean, I'm you should do whatever type
of information that you absorb the best.
I personally love reading. I try to read
everything. So I would just read, kind
of see what interests you, kind of keep
reading this stuff. And I know I
understand like
you know, it can feel like you're
getting a lot done when you're just
consuming information. At some point you
want to actually do something, produce
something, whether that's content,
whether that's you want to write
something, have a investment log.
There's a lot of ways you can do this,
but you know, at some point you're going
to want to start actually producing. It
doesn't have to happen right away. You
can take a few years. I didn't start
writing I was into investing in you
know, since 2012. I didn't start my blog
till 2017. So it took me five years of
reading and doing all this stuff. When I
first started writing, I wasn't that
good at it. I got a lot better over time
as well. So there's a lot of the act of
doing forces you to get better at a lot
of things. So that's what I would say.
>> So how much do you read every day?
>> I used to read a lot more. I just once
again, I just had a kid. So it's
That's not really relevant. Before I had
the kid, I I read a decent amount. I'd
probably say I read about 10 books a
year. Nothing that crazy or impressive
like oh my god, reading a hundred books
a year. I know I mean, my highest I ever
did in a year maybe 25, 30 books. So I
wasn't doing super super crazy volume,
but you know, it's not really the
volume. It's more about just
understanding and just spending time.
And I'm not just reading investment
books. I read a lot of just non-fiction,
non-investment books cuz you learn
things from biology, from, you know,
history, geology, what all these
different things. There's There's
usually pieces in there that are related
to investing in some way or another.
>> One last question. What do you see in
this market the biggest mistake retail
investors are making?
>> I don't have data on this. I don't know
what the mistake is. My guess is people
are probably taking too much risk right
now. Too much undiversified risk. That's
my guess. Like you can own Nvidia and
Microsoft and Apple and you're like,
"Oh, look, I'm diversified." But you're
really They're pretty concentrated in
tech and I know Someone say, "Well,
Nick, isn't the S&P 500 concentrated in
tech?" Yes, it is, but that's even
worse. Only individual stocks in a
handful of companies and thinking you're
diversified. I don't think it's
diversified as people think it is. So,
that's my my counter is I think in
general retail investors are probably
not diversified enough.
>> Thank you, Nick, for your time and I
look forward to a next conversation with
you.
>> Thank you. Appreciate it. If anyone has
questions, feel free to DM me on X,
Instagram, uh LinkedIn, wherever you
find me. I'm happy to answer any
questions you can. Feel free to like
just use a translator if you don't speak
English. I can translate back. It's all
good. Thank you for your time and thank
you for having me on. I truly appreciate
it, Rick.
>> The Wealth Ladder.
>> [music]
>> Bye-bye.
>> I'm so excited. Bye-bye.